<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mastiff Systems</title>
        <description>Mastiff Systems is a small IT services company in Lincoln, Nebraska.</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:33:59 -0500</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 16:33:59 -0500</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.2.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Experimenting with all paid internet services and enshittification </title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As of late I have been thinking a lot about just how bad the internet has gotten. Google search is almost useless as it’s full of ads and not real links for page after page. Content farms and bots have made actual human content hard to find. Social media is just a giant manipulative echo chamber and it’s all done in the name of business and extracting every last penny from the user of the site. If you haven’t heard of the dead internet theory you should read up on it. I don’t know that I fully subscribe to the entire premise which is, that the internet is made by robots not humans but it sure seems like at least some of the internet is dead and that all this content is generated for the advertisers’ benefit. With AI in the mix it certainly seems so and even my local news webpage is so full of ads that it almost seems not credible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily the small web is a growing movement and hopefully it continues to gain traction. The small web is real websites lovingly created by hand by actual people. That’s how we tried to make our own website. This is why we built it from scratch, with no content management engine like WordPress. It’s as good as we can code it. I have a lot to say about the small web but that’s another article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main issues it seems is that the users of these products are not the actual customers of the business. Facebook/Meta and Google’s real customers are the advertisers and not the end user. This leads the business to add features to their products that benefit advertisers even if it hurts the end user experience. Creating an almost &lt;a href=&quot;https://neustadt.fr/essays/against-a-user-hostile-web&quot;&gt;hostile (or user-hateful) end user experience&lt;/a&gt; there is a term for this, where products get worse over time, it’s called enshitification. When I was at DEF CON this last year the &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4EmstuO0Em8?si=zU-0PaI9ixjOE1kE&quot;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt; gave a great talk on the topic and I was in the audience to hear. Is worth a watch and Adam Conover does a great job covering it &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/P7NHABs76mg?si=aXdhpxr3tyMicV-D&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking about the issue with ads and internet I wanted to try a lifestyle experiment. What if I used paid internet services in my personal life to avoid ads? I always like to test things out myself, and I personally HATE ads in any capacity so I set out to try and replace free services with paid ones. If the service is paid then YOU are the customer, not advertisers. When you are the customer it gives the company incentive to make their product the best possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off let’s talk about email. As much as I love Gmail as a product, Google does not care about your privacy at all despite what their marketing may say. You are most valuable to them as a digital asset where they can harvest your data for advertising. There is a company called 37signals that makes a product called Basecamp that we live and die by here at Mastiff. I would even say we could hardly run the business without it. It’s an incredible product that is fairly priced and works great. I wish it was open source but otherwise I have no complaints. I have read the 37signals blog for years and I have really appreciated their views on business and how capitalism should work in a modern tech-driven world. So I was quite intrigued to find that they started their own email service called hey.com. Of course I had to try it out immediately, it costs $5 a month and doesn’t use ads at all nor do they harvest user data, since they charge for the service. Their approach to email is innovative to say the least. I have switched my personal email on over to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey is interesting in that it approaches email differently than Google or Microsoft. It seems their company goal is to make email useful again and to minimize the noise that ends up in all our inboxes. There are basically three sections, the main inbox, a paper trail for receipts and “feed” to see your emails in a large and beautiful way. Another thing it does differently is that you have to approve every sender at first. If you don’t approve of the sender you won’t see their emails. You can also hit “set aside” or “save for later” on your emails and it will remind you to follow up. I use my own domain for my personal email @bleedingpeanutbutter.com that way I can change email providers without changing my email address and hey.com lets me do that. Once you learn the keyboard shortcuts for hey.com it becomes quite powerful and fast to browse through only the emails you want without distraction. It’s a very forward thinking approach and I like seeing the 37signals guys fighting against the email monopoly of Google and Microsoft. We need more and more email hosts in fact. That way email will stay an open standard not controlled by any one company. I highly recommend Hey.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next paid service to discuss is YouTube Premium. As a lifelong musician &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleedingpeanutbutter.com/articles/love-letter-to-the-bass-guitar&quot;&gt;(I started playing bass at 15)&lt;/a&gt;, I have to say it makes me quite jealous to see the kids coming up with YouTube to learn songs and how to play. What an amazing advantage. We had to figure it out through trial and error, or Bass Player magazine or get a VHS instructional video and those were hard to come by and expensive. To have this entire world of knowledge at your fingertips is just incredible. I use YouTube daily for learning about technology or music or gardening or just anything. So I decided to pay the monthly fee to not see ads constantly and it’s well worth the price of admission. Content creators still try and sneak sponsorship marketing in their videos but I’m OK with that as that’s how they fund their channel. I do NOT want to see intrusive and interruptive advertising. In that sense YouTube Premium is well worth the money. When I go to a YouTube video not signed in to my account it’s almost jarring. This one I have to ask how people live without. It’s like two different products, the ads on YouTube standard are so intrusive. This one is a no-brainer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, I wanted to get away from Google search. Google search was once a crowning achievement of the internet, they were the search to beat. But over the last five years or so it has just become a mess. Pages of sponsored ads and bad AI advice is all you see at Google search now. Run don’t walk away. I have been using duckduckgo.com for quite a while, and I would say it’s now superior to Google search but I don’t see how over the long term they won’t fall into the same traps, since their actual customers are their advertisers. Now if you do nothing else after reading this you should switch to duckduckgo.com for search. It’s quite good these days. But then I discovered Kagi.com, it’s a paid-only search engine. A paid search engine is interesting, it’s the only economical business model I can think of where the user of the product is the actual customer. It’s $10 a month, and I thought if $10 a month isn’t worth it for your most used feature on the internet then what is? So I signed up and gave it a go and it’s amazing. It feels like the old internet again, with relevant results and no ads anywhere in the search results. They are also a huge proponent of the small web. I like that a lot. I cannot recommend Kagi enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last thing I wanted to discuss was general news. It’s not difficult to see that news in the US has become completely unreliable. Half the “news” that we see is opinion anyway and post removal of the fairness doctrine in the 80’s it’s become completely polarizing. Years ago I realized that at minimum the goal of the news was to sell tomorrow’s news. The easiest way to do that was to focus on negative stories. Negativity keeps people tuned in. It keeps eyeballs on the station. So let’s not even talk about how news is manipulated by the government and large corporations. At its very core mainstream news WANTS you scared. That just wasn’t for me so I decided to not consume any major news with any regularity. If I want to understand a new bill I read the bill, if I want to see what’s going on with some world event I find the expert and listen to them. I try to get as close to the source as possible. So what’s the best way to get good news with minimum noise? Well that’s still a work in progress but I have found Substack to be fantastic. You can follow an actual scientist or doctor or whatever expert you want quite directly. Now I would say always do your due diligence to vet the person before you follow them and make sure they are credible and always keep a skeptical eye on anything you read. Fact check with peer-reviewed work and fact check the fact checkers. But you can get to the heart of the matter a lot quicker with a direct conversation with the expert. I have also found Patreon to have similar benefits. I subscribe to several Patreon channels myself and I love being able to fund these creators directly rather than have to go through the gatekeeper of big tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The internet can still be a very human place, but it takes some work and apparently some extra money. My day-to-day use of the internet is calming rather than chaotic now that I have almost no ads in my day-to-day world. To keep the internet a free place, maybe we do need to fund these smaller companies that fight to stay independent in a world of “maximum monetization” and tech bros that view people as possible engagement resources to be bled dry. Don’t underestimate the value of your attention to these companies. Right now we are selling it quite cheap and it’s time for a change. For now I will use the paid independent internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Experimenting-with-all-paid-internet-services-and-enshittification/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Experimenting-with-all-paid-internet-services-and-enshittification/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Why Commodore should have ruled the world</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Of all the computer manufactures, Commodore has probably made the most significant impact on the industry and many gamers have never heard of them. Commodore Business Machines was founded in Toronto, Canada in 1962.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many computer companies they began by making calculators. They also invented the first pocket calculator. The company launched several home computer systems but the major success was the Commodore 64 in 1982. After the company’s success, they purchased Amiga Computers. The Amiga computer is, at this point in technological history, the best selling home computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering the amazing systems Commodore produced, it seems the company’s business decisions were not ( amazing. ) Consequently, on Friday, April 29 at 4:10 P.M., Commodore filed for liquidation. Commodore may be gone but the impact they made on the industry remains. Truly, they are the company that did not produce computers strictly for businesses. The home computer became a reality for the general public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Commodore 64 was the first computer I ever owned. It made the Apple IIE’s we where using at school look pathetic. The sound and graphic chip sets were simply amazing, given the technological time period. Then I switched to an Amiga 600. This machine was AWESOME! It made my IBM owning friends quite jealous. Of course I didn’t have a harddrive back then, and the O.S. loaded off floppies every time I wanted to use it. It was only two to three floppies but annoying none the less. The O.S. was worlds ahead of what Microsoft, IBM, and Apple where doing at the time. Had Commodore played their cards right they could currently be where Microsoft is today. Unfortunately, bad business decision after bad business decision caught up with the company. It was mind boggling to watch. How could a company make such amazing products and yet not know how to effectively market those products?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the early 1990’s I had amassed a collection of around 300 Commodore 64 games (if I remember correctly.) A player could get some great games for free. If a person subscribed to publications such as Computer’s Gazette, he/she actually got games with every magazine. The only problem was typing all the code in to get the game/s .That’s right- every magazine came with pages and pages of binary code. All the gamer needed to do was type in that code. It was not uncommon to work 16+ hours of typing. None the less, many classic games came out of the Commodore era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today there is still a huge Commodore following, and there are many emulators for the system. Just google Commodore 64 emulators and see what I mean. If you have the time and want to see a part of gaming history, I recommend playing a few Commodore games, here are some links to a great emulator: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computerbrains.com/ccs64/&quot;&gt;http://www.computerbrains.com/ccs64/&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.c64.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.c64.com/&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commodore…….ahh the memories.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Why-Commodore-should-have-ruled-the-world/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Why-Commodore-should-have-ruled-the-world/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A company scanned Apple cables compared to cheaper knock off’s</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Check out the full report &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lumafield.com/article/usb-c-cable-charger-head-to-head-comparison-apple-thunderbolt-amazon-basics&quot;&gt;USB-C head-to-head comparison&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But just look at the photos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/cable/cables.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mag safe stand&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one reason Apple gets a reputation for being more “expensive” but you
can’t tell me those are the same cables. You really do get what you pay for here in
both speed and longer term reliability. Job’s famously said “Apple doesn’t know
how to make junk” and despite a few missteps here and there, this seems true.
When it comes to technology the devils in the details and Apple does detail better
than anyone.
I’m sure they have good margin on these, of course. But it’s not the highway
robbery people think it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/A-company-scanned-Apple-cables-compared-to-cheaper-knock-offs/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/A-company-scanned-Apple-cables-compared-to-cheaper-knock-offs/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>IOS 17 standby mode</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;How I finally replaced my noise machine and nightstand clock with my iphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my quest for minimalism i’m always looking at how a device can fill multiple rolls so I need less items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the new standby mode I can replace my bed side clock. I have also been playing with using my iPhone to replace my noise machine that I did have setup with HomeKit to turn on at 9pm and off at 11pm. Using my phone is a bit more manual but i like that it’s very intentional. It is nice when I travel that I have the same noise machine on the road as I do at home. So I got a mag safe stand and have that and one HomeKit light by my bed. It looks a lot cleaner and it’s simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/Mag safe stand.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mag safe stand&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a Maxonar stand for $26 and it works great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I’m not overly impressed by how standby mode is setup by default. Why an old school analog clock? Why have it so I can only edit the standby widgets when it’s on a charger? Thats kind of a pain. Hopefully Apple will add features to test. Maybe we will also see third party widgets one day? It could also be that I’m learning how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing some playing with it, I can see that if you swipe over you can change what is displayed. I was able to get a tiny clock in the corner and that works well. Is there a way to customize the color? we will see. See what I have so far…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/display-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display option 1&quot; title=&quot;Display option 1&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/display-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display option 2&quot; title=&quot;Display option 2&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/display-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display option 3&quot; title=&quot;Display option 3&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/display-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display option 4&quot; title=&quot;Display option 4&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also swipe up and down for different clock faces. This is the one I like the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/display-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Display option 5&quot; title=&quot;Display option 5&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the functionality I had hoped for with IOS 17. It seems like a tiny feature but it’s a game changer for me. I loved the giant alarm buttons. It will be interesting to see how I can continue to integrate this in to everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In case you didn’t know. iOS and iPadOS have a sound machine built in. In the past I would use an app to turn my phone in to a white noise machine so I can sleep better at night. It’s a total game changer for me. I think it was added around iOS 14 or 15.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do is launch the settings app, the search background sounds and turn on the sound you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/audio visual settings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Audio and visual settings&quot; title=&quot;Audio and visual settings&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/background sounds settings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Background sounds settings&quot; title=&quot;Background sounds settings&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could even get fancy and create an automation with shortcuts like I did below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/background sounds settings-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Background sounds settings 2&quot; title=&quot;Background sounds settings 2&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this automation, it turns on my noise machine. Turns on my goodnight home automation scene, which locks my doors and turns of all my nights and then plays some calm music in my bedroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you could even start a fitness plus meditation for sleep. Like this one&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/ios/meditation app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Meditation app&quot; title=&quot;Meditation app&quot; width=&quot;400&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is quite remarkable how well this all works. Steve Jobs was all in on the arts and especially music. Where Tim Cook is passionate about health and it shows with things like this. Now I can just bring my stand with me when I’m traveling and in one small package I have my exact setup for sleep that I do at home. Makes sleeping so much easier when I’m not in my own bed. Tying it all in to HomeKit makes it even more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/IOS-17-standby-mode/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/IOS-17-standby-mode/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Using Apple shortcuts to remember to request payment</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I have two of my kids on my car insurance since it’s cheaper for them, so they pay
me directly for it every month rather than pay the bill themselves. I also had them
on my phone plan up until recently. But it’s easy to forget to request that payment
and the kids certainly aren’t motivated to remember. Certainly there was a way to
automate this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution after a lot of trial and error was to use the shortcuts app to create an
automation to request the payment via Apple Pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/shortcuts/image.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/shortcuts/image-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see for my kids. One shortcut each. Then I created a recurring
reminder with a link to the shortcut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blog/shortcuts/image-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Sample Image&quot; title=&quot;Optional Title&quot; width=&quot;800&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I get a pop up reminder on the first of every month, and I just click on the reminder
and it runs the shortcut and requests the money. The system works pretty well and
I haven’t forgotten to ask them since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Using-apple-shortcuts-to-remember-to-request-payment/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Using-apple-shortcuts-to-remember-to-request-payment/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>5 Cool Tips to Upgrade Your Notion Dashboard</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;You’ve made a simple Notion dashboard and are now looking to take it to the next level? Here are a few cool tips to make your dashboard work for you instead of you working on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Relate Multiple Data Sets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have two databases that are related, you can connect them using the relation property so you don’t have to manually update each database separately. This feature is particularly useful for linking projects with tasks, clients with projects, or employees with their assignments. This way, you can easily view and manage related information in one place without duplicating data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Relation&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://peertube-gftks-u25423.vm.elestio.app/videos/embed/7240c82e-41e5-4a11-9bcc-b04d3eb1dc90&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routine Actions in One Click&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the button feature, you can automate routine actions, such as creating a new page, inserting blocks, or editing pages, all with a single click. Buttons are highly customizable, allowing you to tailor their functionality to suit specific needs or workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s try creating a button to add a page to a database in one click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Button&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://peertube-gftks-u25423.vm.elestio.app/videos/embed/29808046-2283-49fe-8261-f1e1644a1c5a&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automate Updates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s another automation trick for databases: Triggers. Triggers reduce the need for manual updates and help keep your data consistent and up to date. For example, if you update an entry, you can set up an automation to automatically notify a group of people, eliminating the need to manually inform them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Trigger&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://peertube-gftks-u25423.vm.elestio.app/videos/embed/9b65d5f6-8bf8-4da2-b06f-5ac10f09b09c&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note:  I am doing this from my private space since this is just a demo but you have to do this in a teamspace in order for this to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create Templates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take advantage of templates. If you have a database where you frequently add similar pages, like client profiles, duplicating a page can require extra effort to remove existing client information. Instead, you can create a template with the same format, allowing you to quickly generate new client profiles without the extra cleanup. This saves time and keeps your workflow efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Template&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://peertube-gftks-u25423.vm.elestio.app/videos/embed/d0da4a35-694d-47ec-a6b6-fb0e58a42b57&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion Formulas&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a fan of Excel? Then you might want to explore Notion’s formulas. Notion formulas allow you to create dynamic, calculated fields within databases, enabling powerful features like calculations, conditional formatting, and logical operations. For example, you can easily track your monthly expenses using a simple formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Formula&quot; width=&quot;860&quot; height=&quot;515&quot; src=&quot;https://peertube-gftks-u25423.vm.elestio.app/videos/embed/caa9f21a-e44c-4937-a55a-d1031f2db41d&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These small changes will definitely transform your work dashboard. Give them a try and see how they can improve your Notion experience!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/5-Cool-Tips-to-Upgrade-Your-Notion-Dashboard/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/5-Cool-Tips-to-Upgrade-Your-Notion-Dashboard/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Tips for Notion Newcomers</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Notion is one of the tools that Mastiff uses to organize our documents and information. It serves as our centralized hub for information, collaboration, and knowledge-sharing. We’ve built our wiki, library, and various work dashboards in Notion. It’s incredibly flexible—think of it like a blank canvas where you can create whatever you need. But I know all that freedom can feel a bit overwhelming at first. So, let me walk you through some basics to help you get started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Customize Your Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can create pages for almost anything and personalize them with various types of content, such as text, images, databases, and more. You can choose from a range of pre-made emojis and icons as visual cues for your pages, or upload your own photos from your computer. You also have the option to select images from Unsplash, which offers a wide range of high-quality stock photos. Although the font color and text background options are somewhat limited, they still provide effective color-coding features for organizing sections and highlighting important information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Organize Your Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I LOVE databases! If you have a lot of pages, a full-page database can become your best friend. Think of it as a super-organized filing cabinet for all your content. Databases are one of the more complex blocks in Notion, but that’s because they offer so much functionality. You can set up automation, apply filters, and sort data efficiently. If you’re just getting started, begin by adding properties tailored to your needs. They’re fantastic for organizing and quickly searching through a pool of pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Same Data, Multiple Views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got your database set up, you can view your data in all sorts of ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table View: A spreadsheet-like layout to view and manage a large amount of data at once. It’s ideal for sorting, filtering, and viewing multiple properties of your data side by side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Board View: A Kanban-style board, perfect for tracking tasks through different stages or categories. Organize tasks by status, priority, or any categorical property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;List View: A simple linear view of data. It provides a minimalist approach to view records one by one with key properties visible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Timeline View: A chronological timeline for your data, great for project planning, tracking deadlines, and scheduling. It provides a visual representation of your tasks or events over time, making it easier to see overlaps and gaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calendar View: For scheduling and managing time-based data like appointments, meetings, or deadlines, Notion’s calendar view is ideal. It allows you to see your tasks and events in a monthly, weekly, or daily format, making it easy to keep track of what’s coming up. A great feature of Notion’s calendar is that it can send you notifications, ensuring you never forget important events. Plus, you can connect it with Google Calendar or Outlook to sync all your schedules in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gallery View: Provides a visual representation of your data, showcasing items as cards with an emphasis on images. It’s ideal for portfolios, mood boards, or any data where visual elements are important, such as team directories or project showcases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chart View: Useful for tracking progress on projects, analyzing performance metrics, or visualizing complex datasets in a more digestible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaborate with Your Team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve created a simple dashboard in Notion, you can easily share it with your team to facilitate collaboration. Notion serves as a central hub for storing team documents, notes, tasks, and databases, all in one accessible location, which helps keep everyone aligned and on the same page. Notion’s permission management features allow you to control access levels, ensuring that sensitive information remains protected while still encouraging effective collaboration. You can assign different permission levels based on each role, providing just the right amount of access each member needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When adding a team member to Notion, you can select their level of access—Full Access, Can Edit, Can Comment, or View Only—depending on their role and responsibilities. For finalized documents or templates, you can use Notion’s “Lock Page” feature to prevent accidental changes. If you’re managing a larger team or organization, creating groups and assigning permissions at the group level is more efficient than setting permissions for each user individually, helping streamline access management and maintain consistent permissions across the team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add Widgets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further enhance your Notion workspace, consider adding widgets. These can include productivity tools and real-time data displays. Platforms like Apption.co offer a variety of options to augment your Notion setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion is incredibly flexible, which is both its strength and the source of initial overwhelm. Take it one step at a time, and don’t be afraid to experiment. As you grow more comfortable with the basics, you’ll discover countless ways to tailor Notion to your specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy organizing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Tips-for-Notion-Newcomers/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Tips-for-Notion-Newcomers/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Data Insurance: Why Do Companies Need It (Or Not)?</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;For starters, What is Data Insurance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We define data insurance for a non-techy person as a safety net for businesses and people worried about cyber threats. It covers costs if sensitive data gets stolen or if there’s a cyberattack. It’s especially crucial today when businesses use a lot of digital tools and face more online risks. With data insurance, they can feel more secure knowing they’re protected financially if something goes wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Insurance vs. Life Insurance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life Insurance: This is a safety net for your family. If something happens to you and you can’t provide for them anymore, life insurance steps in to ensure they’re financially okay. It’s like giving them a big hug of support when you can’t be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Insurance: This acts as a shield. If hackers steal your sensitive information or mess with your online operations, data insurance comes to the rescue. It helps cover the costs of fixing the mess, like hiring experts or paying fines. It’s like having a superhero for your computer files, keeping them safe and sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Should You Get Data Insurance?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider the advantages and disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace of Mind: It’s like having a safety net. If something bad happens to your digital assets, you know you won’t be left hanging financially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helps Cover Costs: If hackers strike or you accidentally lose important data, the insurance helps pay for fixing the mess, such as hiring experts or dealing with legal issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protects Your Business: For companies, it’s like having a guardian for your digital side. If there’s a cyberattack, you can keep running smoothly without worrying about significant financial hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costs Money: Like any insurance, you have to pay for it. Depending on the level of coverage you want, it can add up over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not Foolproof: It won’t stop cyberattacks or data breaches from happening. It just helps you recover financially after the damage is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Policy Limits: Sometimes, there are limits on what the insurance will cover. You need to read the fine print to make sure you’re protected where you need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to research thoroughly before deciding whether to get data insurance. Assess your specific needs, the risks you face, and the coverage options available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data insurance can provide significant benefits, especially in an age where cyber threats are ever-present. However, it’s essential to weigh the costs and limitations to determine if it’s the right choice for you or your business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/Data-Insurance-Why-Do-Companies-Need-It-Or-Not/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/Data-Insurance-Why-Do-Companies-Need-It-Or-Not/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>On Linux, VMware and Broadcom.</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I fell in love with the idea of Linux when I was 15 or 16 years old. I would read magazines about the Linux operating system and the power of open source, which fascinated me. The idea of a free (free as in freedom and free as in free lunch) operating system that anyone could modify for their own specific needs seemed like a gift from the community to the world. Simply incredible. I wanted to run Linux as my primary operating system, but I was also an aspiring musician and had gone on my first real tour when I was 16. I was working as an assistant engineer in a few recording studios, learning the science of audio engineering in the evenings when I wasn’t in class or on the road playing shows, and I had music software I needed to run, none of which worked on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I also discovered emulators. My mom is handicapped (she would kill me if I said she was disabled) from juvenile rheumatoid arthritis, and my dad was a counselor for the state. With my mom’s medical bills and her not being able to generate much income, we didn’t have much money growing up. We were certainly rich in everything that really mattered, but we watched our pennies. I still find myself being pretty thrifty these days as a result of that experience. I watched all my friends getting game consoles like Nintendos and Sega Genesis, but that was just more money than my parents could spare. It was a bit frustrating, but then I discovered emulators and I was hooked. An emulator is a piece of software that tricks your computer into thinking it was a game console, so I could play a lot of those games my friends were playing, right on my computer. I became obsessed with making technology do things it wasn’t necessarily supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, in the late 90’s heard about an UC Berkley startup called VMware that would allow you to run multiple operating systems on one physical host or computer. The person who started the project saw that, in general, servers weren’t fully utilizing all the CPU, RAM, and hard drive space that they had available. They speculated that they could turn one physical server into multiple virtual servers somehow, and that turned into the concept for a hypervisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A hypervisor is an operating system (Windows is the most used operating system for desktop computers and Android on smartphones now is the most popular operating system) that lives on a piece of hardware, like a server, in which you can create virtual computers or machines. Virtual machines are very powerful technology. Essentially, you’ve wrapped a whole computer in one or two files, so you can copy those files all over the place, keep them safe, and move them between multiple hosts in real time without any downtime. It’s rather amazing technology that still feels like magic to me even after all these years, and I thoroughly enjoyed being able to work on that technology in my adult career full-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In one edition of some Linux magazine, there was an ad for VMware and a phone number, so I just called them on the phone and someone actually answered. They were a tiny startup. We discussed Linux and music software and how I could find a way to run both. I was just a dumb kid who didn’t know what he was doing, but it was still amazing that they would just talk to me. At the time, I didn’t get to dig into VMware as much as I would have liked; that would come later. I had no idea when I was 16 that I would be able to have a career in both music technology and corporate IT and how well they actually worked together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I simply fell in love with VMware and the concepts, and as my IT knowledge grew, so did VMware as a company. They certainly had their share of changes in their business as Dell bought them, and they were bought and sold to other companies, but they always managed to navigate the technology landscape in a way that was very good for their users. Most of their users were people like me, server administrators who wanted to squeeze the most performance out of the servers they were working on for their clients. VMware is the backend that powers the world, and almost no one outside of tech circles has heard of them. They make billions of dollars a year now, not bad from a little startup that would answer some 16-year-old kid’s silly questions on the phone for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, a huge conglomerate called Broadcom purchased VMware outright, and it seems their intentions are to raise prices to a ridiculous level, remove any perpetual licensing, and just focus on the absolute largest companies in the world. They’ve made decisions that leave small businesses out of the discussion entirely. Personally, I am increasingly frustrated with this subscription-based world we find ourselves in. I think you should be able to buy software once and use it on your server or computers forever. I hate that you have to pay a monthly fee to use software that you have paid for in the past. VMware’s new licensing model makes it so you will have to pay a subscription on your server forever, or your virtual servers stop working. I didn’t think that was an ethical decision, and VMware’s response to the industry criticisms has been that “Subscription pricing is the industry standard.” I don’t think that’s an acceptable answer, and I don’t care what everyone else does. You need to make the right decision for yourself, and aren’t technology leaders supposed to lead regardless of industry? That’s something I appreciated about Steve Jobs and Apple at the time that he ran it. He didn’t care what the industry was doing; he was going to do what he thought was right and what he thought would make the most sense for his end-users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fear that there’s a larger trend in the tech industry that I’m increasingly unhappy with. I describe it as the tail wagging the dog. All of these tools - servers, hypervisors, printers - are tools to do something in a business, to run the business, to make the business more profitable, to make it work in some way. It seems very backward to me for a tool to dictate the business, rather than the business dictate the use of the tool that it has chosen. It seems that the tech industry has gotten a little too big for its britches, in my opinion, and has decided that they are so vital and important to business as a whole. In some cases, it’s hard to argue. Microsoft Outlook has been the email platform for business for years, despite it not necessarily being the greatest product, but certainly, we can’t be held hostage by these tech companies. We can’t fall into the subscription trap of forever payments for not that much value back other than things keep working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why, after 20 years of being a VMware administrator, we have decided at Mastiff to not do any new VMware projects. We will certainly maintain, upgrade, and take care of our existing VMware install’s, but we will migrate away from VMware in the future. We are moving to a hypervisor product called Proxmox that does a fantastic job for most of what we need and is fully open source, so they won’t ever really have that problem where a big company buys them out. I have personally played with Proxmox off and on for a few years now, and its latest version is quite mature. We also do a lot with Hyper-V, the Microsoft product, and of course, Microsoft Azure and Amazon AWS platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also refuse to install or move to Nutanix, the possible up-and-comer to replace VMware in the corporate world, as they too don’t have perpetual licensing and cost roughly the same as VMware is raising its prices to. Nutanix will trick you with amazing first-year pricing, but then you are trapped, and it’s no better than VMware, and VMware is the more mature product. I hear Nutanix reps give the same line “subscription pricing is industry standard” and it turns my stomach to hear. What a cop out. I thought tech companies didn’t follow the pack? We will work on Nutanix but we wont do a new install with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, our days with VMware are numbered due to them clearly not wanting to take care of small business users’ needs. It’s quite heartbreaking for me, as I’ve loved this technology since I was a teenager, but it seems like there are, at least from a business standpoint, greener pastures elsewhere. We always want to be at the forefront of new technology that can be disruptive to the industry, so it’ll be an interesting few years. Hopefully, this will go down in history as a big giant business mistake for Broadcom and VMware, and companies will learn not to be so disruptive to their users’ everyday lives. Once again, open source saves the day!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/On-Linux-VMware-and-Broadcom/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/On-Linux-VMware-and-Broadcom/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>The Remote Toolkit: Must-Have Tools for Seamless Collaboration</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As a small company with a hybrid work environment that strives to provide in-depth support to fellow small businesses, working collaboratively in an organized manner is important to promptly and accurately attend to clients’ needs. Remote work, though presenting its challenges, can be greatly facilitated with the right tools. Of course, tools should be tailored to your business type and organizational needs, but we found some tools that may help you transition from a traditional workspace to having an efficient virtual work hub. Here are some tools that have proven beneficial for Mastiff in running its operations smoothly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notion is a versatile productivity tool known for note-taking but offers much more. With a tailored fit space for your business, it can serve as a centralized hub for your team’s collaborative efforts, allowing you to manage databases, tasks, and customize templates for various workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I like about this, aside from its versatility, is that we can incorporate our creativity into organizing the company with style. Something I hope they can improve is their mobile app functionality. It is quite functional, but I mostly just use it for viewing information from pages because it does not match the richness of the desktop version, especially for complex tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basecamp is web-based project management software that organizes multiple projects by providing designated spaces for each one. Its features include assigning to-do lists, group and one-on-one chats, and setting up people working on the project - whether employees, outside collaborators, or clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that gives me peace of mind is having a place for everything and everything is in its place. With Basecamp’s feature of allowing us to create specific spaces for a certain project, we can organize files, people who are working on it, and everyone can see the project’s progress. I just hope it can be integrated with more online tools without having to use a third-party app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helpwise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Helpwise is a comprehensive CRM platform with customizable plans based on your intended usage. It’s excellent for logging customer interactions, tracking sales, and executing effective marketing across different platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miscommunication can be a challenge in a remote work environment, so we try as much as we can to be on the same page, especially in client interactions. HubSpot has a feature that allows us to log every email, call, text, and even communication-related task on every contact we have saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecteam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connecteam is a mobile workforce management platform with a clean interface. It’s great for an employee directory and engagement, featuring a time clock for schedule management, customizable forms for evaluations and feedback, and an updates feed for schedule-related announcements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is small business-friendly. With their free plan, you can access a great deal of access to their features good for 10 members. It may be overwhelming at first, but they provide short demos for every feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeper is a password manager designed to securely store and manage information. It includes a tool for generating strong, unique passwords to reduce the risk of cyber threats, along with two-factor authentication (2FA) for an extra layer of protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone has at least once struggled to remember their passwords, and I did too. I work mainly on keeping the company organized and deal with a lot of information; having a secure place to put sensitive information is one less thing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great news! All of these have their own mobile applications, allowing you to access them at your fingertips and work on the go. It is important to know your organization’s needs before searching for tools so they will fit your intended usage, but these are some of the tools that have contributed to Mastiff Systems’ progress in its mission to be organized from within, allowing us to provide seamless service that establishes and maintains successful client relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Remote-Toolkit-Must-Have-Tools-for-Seamless-Collaboration/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/The-Remote-Toolkit-Must-Have-Tools-for-Seamless-Collaboration/</guid>
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>